JAYSON MONTERROSO SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT

Software Developer for wide variety of global clients, websites and applications, With vast array of knowledge in many different front end and back end languages, responsive frameworks, databases, mobile development and best code practices., More than 10 years of experience in Web Development. Compromised to learn and improve every day my hard/soft skills.

OVERVIEW EXPERIENCE

GORILLA LOGIC

Full Stack Developer | August 2017 - present

- Redesigned/Migrated marketing website for a SASS DevOps company.
- Developed global UI including assets/styles/scripts.
- Migrated all posts and content from Wordpress to Jekyll(Ruby).
- Implemented a third party CMS Service using Node+Contentful+Jekyll
- Implemented the continuos integration infrastructure using Netlify

ELEVEN SYSTEMS (FORMER JETSON SYSTEMS)

Software Developer | April 2016 - August 2017

- Creation of scalable Angular Modules for a large web application
- Hooked up restful services with complex data using Angular 2
- Implemented complex financial charts using Highcharts IS.
- Created Financial Module Page UI/UX, to support data coming from Salesforce.

PRODIGIOUS LATAM

Principal Layer Engineer | April 2013 - August 2016

- Redesigned/Migrated website for smartusa.com
- Responsibilities included UI planning/development/testing and
- Created multiple facebook social applications and games.
- Created 3D interior viewer for vehicles in website using three.js
- Implementation of changes per client request based on compositions provided

CONTACT DETAILS

Alajuela, Costa Rica +(506) 8706-6404 jayson.monterroso@gmail.com http://jaysonmonterroso.com

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

UNIVERSIDAD ADVENTISTA DE CENTRO AMERICA

Bachelor of Computer Systems Engineering

EXPERTISE

Web Development Coding & Programming Search Engine Optimization Cross-Browser Compatibility Site Troubleshooting UX & UI Design Agile Methodologies Hosting & Maintenance

Information Architecture

TECNICAL SKILLS

Back-End Development

Node, PHP

DevOps

Front End Development:

HTML5, CSS/SASS/Compass/Neat, Javascript (ES 5/6) Bootstrap, Foundation,

Front-End Javascript Frameworks: Angular 5 &

Angular S (1.6), React, Highcharts. js, Backbone. js, Sencha Touch, ¡Query, Three.js

Javascript Tools: Webpack, Gulp, Babel CLI,

Angular CLI, Grunt, Node CLI Tools

Native Mobile Javascript Frameworks: React

Native, Nativescript

Databases MongoDB, MySQL, MS SQL Server, DynamoDB S3,

EXPERIENCE

ACCENTURE

Web Developer | 2011 - 2013

- Worked as web developer for several projects with different global clients, websites/apps based on client requirements.
- Created hybrid mobile application (iOs/Android) using Sencha Touch 1.5 and 2.0 javascript framework | Merck Pharmaceutical.
- Worked as backend developer(php) creating the content and website architecture and functionality for a wordpress website. *costaricavacations.com*.
- Created a Wordpress Plugins to support external Razuna server upload of assest for assets management.
- Worked in the creation of a SPA to display college sports scores/statistics using Backbone.js and consuming restful services | Gatorade

BOSZ DIGITAL

Web Developer | 2011 | Bank of America

- Created mobile and web landing pages to support local/global marketing campaigns, based on client requirements and specifications.
- Implemented best practices for accessibility across all landing pages.
- Certified with ADA certification for accessibility coding best practices

LATITUDE TEN NORTH

Full Stack Developer | 2010 - 2011

Responsible for evaluating the technological environment and scope of the projects and suggest possible development stacks along with timelines

Web Developer (using PHP and CMS based on PHP Wordpress/Expression Engine) creating functional backend/frontend websites based on detailed requirements from clients.

Worked for several religious and political projects organisations in the United States (Ohio GOP/Good Samaritan)

ELECTRODOMESTICOS CASABLANCA

Full Stack Developer | 2007 - 2010

- Full Stack Developer responsible for creation of corporate Intranet, and global website.
- In charge of design, back end, front end and content management.
- In charge of migrate MS SQL Server database to MySQL inventory tables in order to be consistent with products on internal and external website.
- Intranet was developed using a financial web service in order to determine if a client was able to receive a credit, by using his personal id.

PROJECTS

YOURSECRETCODE.COM

S3 Migration/Node Refactoring | 2017

- Migration of current self-served Node instance to a Serverless Architecture using Serverless Application Framework.
- Migration of Mongo Database to AWS DynamoDB.
- Refactoring codebase based in node in order to improve performance and code readability.
- Implementation of ES6 in the website core functions which is the book creation/generation based on user input.

TALENTO HUMANO

Mobile Application / Backoffice Web Application /Api Services/DevOps

- Responsible for creation of a native mobile application for iOS/Android using nativescript
- Creation of a single web application Back Office System to manage the web application and mobile application.
- Creation of backend services using GraphQL to support both application and back office web app,
- The scope of the project is to have a internal database of all employees and also tracks labor hours along with geolocation for internal use.

LATITUDE TEN NORTH

Full Stack Developer | 2010 - 2011

Responsible for evaluating the technological environment and scope of the projects and suggest possible development stacks along with timelines.

Web Developer (using PHP and CMS based on PHP Wordpress/Expression Engine) creating functional backend/frontend websites based on detailed requirements from clients.

Worked for several religious and political projects organisations in the United States (Ohio GOP/Good Samaritan)

ELECTRODOMESTICOS CASABLANCA

Full Stack Developer | 2007 - 2010

- Full Stack Developer responsible for creation of corporate Intranet, and global website.
- In charge of design, back end, front end and content management.
- In charge of migrate MS SQL Server database to MySQL inventory tables in order to be consistent with products on internal and external website.
- Intranet was developed using a financial web service in order to determine if a client was able to receive a credit, by using his personal id.